## BenVineyard

SR. FULLSTACK SOFT WARE ENGINEER

## **HELLO WORLD!**

My name is Ben Lynn Vineyard IV and I am an 40 year old software engineer. I eat, drink, and sleep technology & software. I have been developing software professionally for over 20 years. I am passionate about what I do, confident I can deliver a viable customer product, and skilled enough to make it fly.



### EDUCATION -

**UNIVERSITY OF NORTH CAROLINA:** BS - COMPUTER SCIENCE - 2001 I graduated with a bachelor of science degree in computer science in 2001. I possessed a 3.45 GPA.



## JOB EXPERIENCE—

PRINCIPAL ENGINEER: KASEYA 2018 - Present
Architecting software solutions on the MEAN (mongoDB, express, angularJS, & nodeJS) stack. The SaaS solutions are hosted on

Microsoft's Azure Cloud.

LEAD SOFTWARE DEVELOPER: STATION CASINOS 2016 - 2018 Leading Agile teams developing software on the MEAN (mongoDB, express, angularJS, & nodeJS) stack. We are currently migrating off of an IBM DB2 stack onto nodeJS microservices. We are currently hosting our new stack in Docker containers across Microsoft Azure and Amazon AWS platforms.

FOUNDER/CTO: BOTVANA 2013 - 2016

Created search engine optimized, Wordpress-based websites for clients of SEO-For-Lawyers.com. Consulted on a handful of angularJS front-end and nodeJS backend projects.

#### SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER III: IGT 2011 - 2014

I wrote software and provided technical leadership for a team of engineers in both the US & China for IRC and CTA products from IGT's Advantage Suite. The core technologies were C#, WCF, & MSSOL.

SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER: COSMOPOLITAN LAS VEGAS 2010 - 2011
Architected & developed a queuing infrastructure for OpenTable vendor system, so that it could integrate from their SQL 2008 based database to both our hotel registration system and master data management system (DataFlux) using C# & MSSQL Service Broker.

#### SR. SOFTWARE DEVELOPER: AIS 2010 - 2010

Supported and maintained existing ASP.NET & Silverlight web applications with C# managed code-base. Architected & developed a cross-site casino progressive system using WCF 4.0 for message transport, Silverlight 4.0 for the user interface, and SQL 2008 for the data store.



Haywood Dr, Las Vegas, NV

702.913.6903

ben@benvineyard.com

w www.benvineyard.com

www.github.com/benvineyard

**b** www.twitter.com/benvineyard

in linkedin.com/in/benvineyard

## **SKILLS-**

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

ASP.NET

nodeJS

C#

angularJS

SQL/NoSQL

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

Communication

Teamwork

Creativity

Leadership

Management

# BenVineyard



## JOB EXPERIENCE-

.NET SOFTWARE DEVELOPER: TECH RESULTS 2009 - 2009 Supported and maintained existing SSIS packages. Designed and authored Silverlight 3.0 web application with WCF back-end. Supported and maintained existing web application software comprised of ASP.NET front-ends and WCF back-ends.

PROGRAMMER/ANALYST: STATION CASINOS 2005 - 2009 Designed and wrote web and pc applications in VB6, VB.NET, & C#. Designed and implemented .NET-based service plug-ins in a Service Oriented Architecture (SOA). Designed and implemented C# web services and WCF services, exposing customer data on an AS400 IBM mainframe.

PROGRAMMER: SILVER STATE SCHOOLS CREDIT UNION 2003 - 2005 Maintained & serviced an ASP/COM based online banking system. Co-Authored and maintained a VB.NET implementation of the aforementioned online banking system, written from the ground up. Co-Authored and maintained a PHP port of the .NET version of the online system.

#### SYSTEM ENGINEER: CAPCO ENT. 2001 - 2003

Designed user interface for Player Rewards kiosk prototype. originally targeted for Mandalay Bay Casino, using Adobe Photoshop using a PHP based frontend and MySQL database backend. Engineered the Debian Linux based environment that the prototype operated in.

#### WEB DEVELOPER/DESIGNER: ETRONIXX 1998 - 2001

Created basic informational websites utilizing HTML/DHTML/XHTML. Created web applications using classic ASP and PHP.



#### CERTIFIED SCRUM DEVELOPER: SCRUM ALLIANCE 2013

Performed training through Scrum Alliance while employed at IGT and received my Certified Scrum Developer (CSD) certificate in 2013.

#### **CERTIFIED SCRUM MASTER: SCRUM ALLIANCE 2013**

Performed training through Scrum Alliance while employed at IGT and received my Certified Scrum Master (CSM) certificate in 2013.